Guide to the Richard Hell Papers 1944-2003 (Bulk 1969-2003) MSS.140
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series XV: Videotape Recordings
  - Subseries B: Originals
    - 3/4" Umatic, and VHS. Meet Theresa Stern, and Rebels: A Journey Underground., undated (Box 36, Media 140.0001 - 140.0021)
    - 3/4" Umatic, and VHS. Richard Hell related video recordings. Blank Generation, etc., undated (Box 37, Media 140.0022 - 140.0047)
    - Various music videos, tribute performances including 9/11/2001 tapes and "History of Rock-n-Roll" box set, undated (Box 38, Media 140.0048 - 140.0072)
  - Subseries C: Submasters - CLOSED
    CLOSED
    - Theresa Master, undated (Box PM 7, Case 140.0351)
      Source ID
      140.0001
    - Meet Theresa Stern, undated (Box PM 7, Case 140.0354)
      140.0002
    - Theresa Stern Rejected 1st Cut, undated (Box PM 7, Case 140.0360)
      140.0006
    - "Meet Theresa Stern", undated (Box PM 7, Case 140.0357)
      140.0003
    - Theresa Stern, 1st Cut Better, undated (Box PM 7, Case 140.0363)
      140.0007
    - Meet Theresa Stern (Box PM 9, Case 140.0347)
  - Subseries D: Preservation Masters - CLOSED
    - ID: 140.0346, 140.0350 - 140.0362 (Box PM 38)
- Series XVI: Sound Recordings
  - Subseries A: Access Copies
    Sound recordings have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  - Subseries B: Originals
    Includes original analog and some digital copies of Richard Hell’s official releases and his own recordings of live performances, studio sessions, demos, and alternate takes. Access copies may not be available for consultation, please ask a Fales archivist.
    - Audiocassette, 2" inch, 1/2" inch and 1/4" inch open reel, compact disk and DAT format materials., undated (Box 39, Media 140.0073 - 140.0110, Box 40, Media 140.0111 - 140.0133, Box 41, Media 140.0134 - 140.0184, Box 42, Media 140.0185 - 140.0207, Box 43, Media 140.0208 - 140.0216, Box 44, Media 140.0217 - 140.0219, Box 45, Media 140.0220 - 140.0224, Box 46, Media 140.0225 - 140.0228, Box 47, Media 140.0229 - 140.0236, Box 48, Media 140.0237 - 140.0254, Box 49, Media 140.0255 - 140.0265, Box 56, Media 140.0365 - 140.0369)
- Oversize - Series I: Manuscripts
  - Subseries A: Journals and Notebooks
    Journals and notebooks kept by Richard Hell; includes loose materials from notebooks.
    - Journal 1980 - 83 materials, 1980-1983 (Box 32, Folder 8A)
    - Journal 1986 - materials (Box 32, Folder 21A)
- Oversize – Series I: Manuscripts
  - Subseries B: Sketchbooks and Scrapbooks
    Richard Hell’s sketchbooks and scrapbooks.
    - Scrapbook (oversize box 1), undated (Box 32, Folder 63A)
    - Letraset- press type, undated (Box 32, Folder 63B)
    - Scrapbook Contents, clippings in illustrated folder, undated (Box 32, Folder 63C)
    - Scrapbook Contents, unsigned painting, undated (Box 32, Folder 63)
    - Scrapbook Contents, unsigned painting, "Love is Hell", undated (Box 32, Folder 63E)
    - Scrapbook Contents, clippings packet, undated (Box 32, Folder 63)
    - Scrapbook Contents, mounted drawings, undated (Box 32, Folder 63G)
    - Scrapbook Contents, painting by Chris Kidd, undated (Box 32, Folder 63H)
    - Scrapbook Contents, painting on back of Voidoids flyer, undated (Box 32, Folder 63I)
    - Scrapbook Contents, Voidoids/Television, flyers and posters, undated (Box 32, Folder 63J)
    - Scrapbook Contents, drawing attached to fan club flyer, undated (Box 32, Folder 63K)
    - Scrapbook Contents, unsigned sketch of RH, undated (Box 32, Folder 63L)
    - Scrapbook Contents, sketch of Poe by Sue Beschta, undated (Box 32, Folder 63M)
    - Scrapbook Contents, sketch of RH, by Susan Springfield, undated (Box 32, Folder 63N)
    - Scrapbook Contents, drawing Chris Parker, 1978 (Box 32, Folder 63O)
    - Scrapbook Contents, painting, unsigned, undated (Box 32, Folder 63P)
    - Scrapbook Contents, painting of RH on stage, unsigned, undated (Box 32, Folder 63Q)
    - Scrapbook Contents, sketch of hand by Victoria Gondolf, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 63R)
    - Scrapbook Contents, pencil drawing by Lisa Kistal, undated (Box 32, Folder 63S)
    - Scrapbook Contents, Hell’s Kitchen, undated (Box 32, Folder 63T)
    - Scrapbook Contents, unsigned collage, undated (Box 32, Folder 63U)
    - Sketchbook Pages, 1980 (Box 33, Folder 63V)
    - Sketchbook, undated (Box 33, Folder 63W)
    - Sketchbook, undated (Box 33, Folder 63X)
- Oversize - Series I: Manuscripts
  - Subseries D: Prose
    Richard Hell’s prose manuscripts.
    - Sketchbook, undated (Box 33, Folder 67)
    - Slum Journal #1 East Village Eye with manuscript corrections, 1979 (Box 33, Folder 100)
- Oversize – Series II: Correspondence
  Richard Hell’s correspondence, arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  - Partial Name, undated (Box 33, Folder 562A)
- Oversize - Series III: Projects
  - Subseries F: Music
    - Waxpaper/ NYC w/ article "Richard Hell and the Voidoids…” by Lester Bangs, 1977 (Box 33, Folder 656A)
    - Sleeve, undated (Box 34, Folder 642A)
    - Cover, undated (Box 34, Folder 642B)
  - Oversize - Subseries N: Heroin Research
    Materials relating to research and composition of Richard Hell’s articles on heroin use from 1986 to 1996.
    - Getting Real About Getting High, 1986 (Box 34, Folder 768A)
    - Artifact Proof with Corrections, undated (Box 34, Folder 943)
  - Oversize - Subseries W: Theresa Stern Story
    - Theresa Stern Story – Re-recording Cue Sheet, undated (Box 34, Folder 1065A)
  - Oversize - Subseries X: Go Now (1996)
    Manuscript drafts of and materials relating to the publication of Richard Hell’s novel, published by Scribner’s.
    - Cover art (US), undated (Box 34, Folder 1120A)
    - Cover Art, (UK), undated (Box 34, Folder 1124A)
  - Oversize - Subseries Z: Gustav Hasford (c.1995-98)
    Materials relating to Richard Hell’s research on Gustave Hasford, a former marine, novelist and convicted bibliomaniac.
    - Research Materials, undated (Box 34, Folder 1228A)
  - Oversize - Subseries AB: Cuz Editions
    Materials relating to Richard Hell’s small press imprint, which published books by Richard Hell, Maggie Dubris, Rene Ricard, Ron Pagett and others.
    - Cover Art, undated (Box 34, Folder 1279A)
    - HOT and COLD, cover art, undated (Box 34, Folder 1236A)
  - Oversize – Series V: Photography
    - B&W, 8x10 photo of RH father, Kentucky, ca.1950 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - B&W, 8x10 photo of RH mother, ca.1950 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - B&W, 8x10 photo of unidentified man [RH’s father], undated (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - 3-pages of B&W photos of RH, mother, father, and sister pasted to paper with annotations by Carolyn, RH’s mother, 1951-1952 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Letter from RH’s mother with drawing by RH, Jul 1962 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - B&W, 11 x 13", photo of RH in concert, Photographer: Tama Bruder, 1979 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - B&W, 11 x 13", photo of RH in concert, Photographer: Tama Bruder, 1979 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - B&W, 10 x14", RH and unidentified woman standing in street, undated (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - B&W, 10x 14" Unidentified woman standing in bra and pants, undated (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - B&W, 11x 13", RH in concert, Photographer: Tama Bruder, undated (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - B&W, 11x 13",RH kneeling, holding microphone, Photographer: Tama Bruder, undated (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - B&W, 11x 13," contact sheet of RH and Television, ca.1974 (Box 35, Folder A12)
    - B&W, 5.5x12", two men sitting 4 separate photos, negatives and 5.5x12" 3 negatives of "Television", ca.1974 (Box 35, Folder A13)
    - B&W, 10x 14," RH wearing Voidoids t-shirt, ca.1977 (Box 35, Folder B14)
    - B&W, 11x 13,", RH wearing Voidoid t-shirt, photographer Eileen Polk, 1977 (Box 35, Folder B15)
    - Color, 12x18", RH with Voidoids, undated (Box 35, Folder B16)
    - Scrapbook of photos 1982, From Babette (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - B&W, 11 x 13", RH and daughter Ruby, Photographer: Mariana Cook, 1992 (Box 35, Folder D18)
    - Color, 8x12", RH standing in front of brick wall with graffiti, for Chelsea Hotel magazine., undated (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - Color, 8x12", RH and man standing in front of brickwall with graffiti, for Chelsea Hotel magazine., undated (Box 35, Folder 20)
    - Color, 8 x12", W. Burroughs with cane., undated (Box 35, Folder H21)
    - B&W, 13x11", RH in hallway., undated (Box 35, Folder 22)
    - B&W, 6x8" RH pointing at ring, Photographer: Melanie Werner, 1996 (Box 35, Folder 23)
    - B&W, 8x13", Two unidentified men, promotional photo, undated (Box 35, Folder 24)
    - B&W, cut out of man on stool and B&W band photo with cutouts., undated (Box 35, Folder 25)
    - Mounted B&W photograph of young girl in wedding veil., undated (Box 35, Folder 26)
    - B&W, 10x8", Print of "Ruby-A Gem", man and woman tap dancing on gigantic typewriter, United Press International, 1937 (Box 35, Folder 27)
    - B&W 8x10" print of Donut Hut, and color 3x5" print of metal pot., undated (Box 35, Folder 1483)
- Oversize - Series VI: Artwork
  - Artwork- Photocopy of Ink Drawing, By Nick Zedd of Richard Hell, 1983 (Box 21A, Folder 1491B)
  - Artwork- Framed Drawing of Shoe and photograph of foot, By Richard Hell (signed), undated (Box 21A, Folder 1491)
  - Artwork- Colored pencil drawing of "Extreme Closeup of Human Eye," artist unknown, 1978 (Box 21B, Folder 1491E)
  - Artwork- Framed Watercolor Painting, "Welcome to Japan"- by Naomi, undated (Box 21B, Folder 1491)
  - Artwork-Pencil Drawing- "Your Message Here" Artist Unknown, undated (Box 21B, Folder 1491G)
  - Artwork- Small photo of steamships in red frame "Heritage"- [by Diego Cortez], 1977 (Box 21B, Folder 1491H)
  - Artwork- small photo of people rowing in red frame 1977 "My Latin"-[by Diego Cortez] (Box 21B, Folder 1491I)
  - Artwork- Framed Etching-Artist Unknown, undated (Box 21A, Folder 1491A)
  - Artwork- Acrylic Painting of Richard Hell Artist Unknown, undated (Box 21A, Folder 1491C)
- Oversize - Series VIII: Periodicals/ News Clippings
  - Subseries B: Periodicals/Tabloids
    - Tabloids: Ace Weekly, Vol. 12, no.35, Nov. 16, 2000 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: Amos Poe's Autograph, August 15, 1977 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: Cashbox, Vol 38, No. 30, Jan.1977 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: The Daily Telegraph, Australian pub., July 1993 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: Damage, Vol 1, No. 8, August 1980 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: Deluxe, (2), undated (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: EG, July 2, 1993 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: FILE, Vol.3, NO.3, Spring 1977 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: Foxtrot, Dec. 1976 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: Girl Groups, undated (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: Gloria, NO.3, May- June 1983 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: Independent America, New York Rocker, May, 1982 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: Melody Maker, Sept.14, 1974 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: Melody Maker, Vol. 51, No. 48, 1976 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: Melody Maker, Vol. 51, no 48, 1976 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: Melody Maker, Feb. 26, 1983 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: Melody Maker, May 18, 1991 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: Mouth of the Rat, Sept. 1980 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: Nerve; No. 44, April 1988 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: New Age/Merde Nouveau, 1977 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: New Age/Merde Nouveau II, Jan & Feb. 1978 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: Newave, Vol.1, No.1, April 1980 (2) (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: New York Newsday, January 4, 1990 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: New York Post, Vol. 129, No. 221, August 6, 1980 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: New York Post, vol. 200, no. 57, Jan. 11, 2004 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: Punk, vol.1, No. 7, Feb 1977 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: Punk, No. 10, 1977 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: Punk 1978 Calendar (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: Ritz Newspaper, No. 75, (newspaper and correspondence), 1975 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: Rolling Stone, No. 329, Oct. 30, 1980 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: Search & Destroy, No. 9, 1978 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: TAO, New Jersey Arts Newspaper, John Enslin Correspondence, Flyer, Review, 1975 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: Travelers Digest, Vol.1, No,2, 1977 (2) (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: Travelers Digest, Vol.1, No.3, (2), 1978 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: Variety, Vol. 307, No.3, May 1982 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: X Motion Picture Magazine, Vol. 2, Issue 2&3, 1978 (Box 23A)
    - Tabloids: The Aquarian, Vol X, No.91, May 7- 21, 1975 (Box 23B)
    - Tabloids: The Aquarian, vol 10, no.98 September 10, 1975 (Box 23B)
    - Tabloids: The Aquarian Vol X, NO.99, Sept. 24, 1975 (Box 23B)
    - Tabloids: East Village Eye, Vol 1, No. 5, October, 1979 (Box 23B)
    - Tabloids: East Village Eye Vol, 1, No.6, Thanksgiving, 1979 (Box 23B)
    - Tabloids: East Village Eye, Vol II, No. 7, Feb., 1980 (Box 23B)
    - Tabloids: East Village Eye, Vol. II, No. 8, March 16, 1980 (Box 23B)
    - Tabloids: East Village Eye, Vol. II, No.10, April 13, 1980 (Box 23B)
    - Tabloids: East Village Eye, Vol.II, No.13, Summer, 1980 (Box 23B)
    - Tabloids: East Village Eye, Vol. IV, No.24, Aug., 1982 (Box 23B)
    - Tabloids: Sounds, Feb. 26, 1983 (Box 23B)
    - Tabloids: East Village Eye, Vol, V, No. 43, May 1984 (Box 23B)
    - Tabloids: International Eye, (retrospective of The East Village Eye ) Jan. 1987 (Box 23B)
    - Tabloids: The Musical Express, June 7, 1975 (Box 23B)
    - Tabloids: The Musical Express, November 20, 1976 (Box 23B)
    - Tabloids: The Musical Express, April 15, 1978 (Box 23B)
    - Tabloids: NME, New Musical Express, Jan. 6, 1979 (Box 23B)
    - Tabloids: NME, New Musical Express, April 5, 1980 (Box 23B)
    - Tabloids: NME, New Musical Express, Feb. 12, 1983 (Box 23B)
    - Tabloids: NME, New Musical Express, Dec. 15, 1984 (Box 23B)
    - Tabloids: NME, New Musical Express, June 20, 1992 (Box 23B)
    - Tabloids: Sounds, April 23, 1977 (Box 23B)
    - Tabloids: Sounds, January 13, 1979 (Box 23B)
    - Tabloids: The Village Voice, Vol XIX, No.9, Feb 28, 1974 (Box 23C)
    - Tabloids: The Village Voice, Vol.XX, No.27, Jul 7, 1975 (Box 23C)
    - Tabloids: The Village Voice, Vol. XXII, No.6, Feb.7, 1977 (Box 23C)
    - Tabloids: The Village Voice, Vol XX, NO. 27, July 7, 1981 (Box 23C)
    - Tabloids: Voice Literary Supplement, Issue 97, July/Aug, 1991 (Box 23C)
    - Tabloids: Voice Literary Supplement, No.130, Nov., 1994 (Box 23C)
    - Tabloids: Greater New York Weekly Soho News, Vol. IX, No. 22, March 10-16, 1982 (Box 23C)
    - Tabloids: Weekly Soho News, Vol. V, No. 5, Nov. 3-9, 1977 (Box 23C)
    - Tabloids: Soho News Weekly, Vol. III, No.25, Mar 25, 1976-Mar 31, 1976 (Box 23C)
    - Tabloids: The Soho Weekly, Vol.1, No.38, June 27, 1974 (Box 23C)
    - Tabloids: The Soho Weekly, Vol, II, No. 17, Jan. 30, 1975 (Box 23C)
    - Tabloids: The Soho Weekly, Vol. II, No.49, Sept,11, 1975 (Box 23C)
    - Tabloids: Interview, Vol. V, No. 3, (2), Mar 1975 (Box 23D)
    - Tabloids: Interview, Vol V, No.4, Apr 1975 (Box 23D)
    - Tabloids: Inteveriew, Vol. V, No. 5, May 1975 (Box 23D)
    - Tabloids: Interview, Vol.VII, No. 1, Jan 1972 (Box 23D)
    - Tabloids: Inteview, Vol VII, no. 6, Jun 1977 (Box 23D)
    - Tabloids: Interview, Vol VII, No7, Jul 1977 (Box 23D)
    - Tabloids: Interview, Vol VII, No. 8, Aug 1977 (Box 23D)
    - Tabloids: Interview, Vol. VII, No.9, Sep 1977 (Box 23D)
    - Tabloids: Interview, Vol, VII, No. 10, Oct 1977 (Box 23D)
    - Tabloids: Interview, Vol, VII, No. 11, Nov 1977 (Box 23D)
    - Tabloids: Interview, Vol, VIII, No.1, Jun 1978 (Box 23D)
    - Tabloids: Interview, Vol. VIII, No.4, Apr 1978 (Box 23D)
    - Tabloids: Interview, Vol. X, No. 9, Sep 1980 (Box 23D)
    - Tabloids: Interview, Vol. XVI, No.4, Apr 1986 (Box 23D)
    - Tabloids: New York Rocker, Vol, 1 #1, Feb 1976 (Box 23D)
    - Tabloids: New York Rocker, Vol, 1, #3, May 1976 (Box 23D)
    - Tabloids: New York Rocker, PIX, #1, May 1979 (Box 23D)
    - Tabloids: New York Rocker #22, Sep 1979 (Box 23D)
    - Tabloids: New York Rocker #27, 1980 (Box 23D)
    - Tabloids: New York Rocker #33, Nov 1980 (Box 23D)
    - Tabloids: New York Rocker #35, Jan 1981 (Box 23D)
    - Tabloids: New York Rocker #38, Apr 1981 (Box 23D)
    - Tabloids: New York Rocker #39, May 1981 (Box 23D)
    - Tabloids: New York Rocker #53, Sep 1982 (Box 23D)
  - Subseries C: Clippings
    - Newspaper Clippings, undated (Box 23E, Folder 1615A)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1970 (Box 23E, Folder 1615B)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1980 (Box 23E, Folder 1615C)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1990 (Box 23E, Folder 1615)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 2000 (Box 23E, Folder 1615E)
- Oversize - Series IX: Artifacts and Objects
  - Commercially printed backdrop for concert performance with cartoon figures and hand-painted japanese characters, 1990; 140.2.001; 1 item one banner; 120" x 100" (Box custom objects housing, Item 140.2.001)
    Banners.
- Oversize - Series XI: Large Design Elements and Source Materials
  Materials Richard Hell used to produce flyers, posters and publications.
  - Design Elements: Large transparencies of RH and The Voidoids, Photographer: Roberta Bayley, (4) and collages, by RH, undated (Box 29, Folder 1684)
  - Design Elements: Red scrapbook of drawings clippings on lined paper, artist unknown, (2), undated (Box 29, Folder 1685)
  - Design Elements: Collage of newspaper paper, "Don’t Know," artist unknown, undated (Box 29, Folder 1686)
  - Design Elements: Pencil drawing on tracing Voidoids, press material, artist unknown, undated (Box 29, Folder 1687)
  - Design Elements: color print of RH and, undated (Box 29, Folder 1688)
  - Design Elements: "My name is Richard Hell," transparency in Red and Black, artist unknown, undated (Box 29, Folder 1688)
  - Design Elements: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 29, Folder 1690)
  - Design Elements: Pencil Drawings with writing on back, artist unknown (4), undated (Box 29, Folder 1691)
  - Design Elements: Copy of poster for RH and the Voidoids at the Village Gate, undated (Box 29, Folder 1692)
  - Design Elements: for posters, "True Life present Television," "True Life presents the Heartbreakers," "True Life present Voidoids", undated (Box 29, Folder 1693)
  - Design Elements: RH and the Voidoids Fanclub, Photographer: Roberta Bayley, undated (Box 29, Folder 1694)
  - Design Elements: Richard "Hell" Robot and Caveman on Polyester, RH Headshot on polyester, undated (Box 29, Folder 1695)
  - Design Elements: Miscellaneous 1, undated (Box 29, Folder 1696)
  - Design Elements: Miscellaneous 2, undated (Box 29, Folder 1697)
  - Design Elements: Miscellaneous 3, undated (Box 29, Folder 1698)
  - Design Elements: Sound & Vision, by RH, 2001-2002 (Box 29, Folder 1699)